aoi hoshi ni senritsu ga hashiru
a
o
i
ho
shi
ni
se
n
ri
tsu
ga
ha
shi
ru
A shudder runs over the blue planet
푸른 지구에 전율이 흐른다
kuroi arashi chikazuku toki
ku
ro
i
a
ra
shi
chi
ka
zu
ku
to
ki
It's the time the dark storm approaches
검은 폭풍이 닥쳐오는 순간
kokoro no oku de mezameru HERO
ko
ro
no
o
ku
de
me
za
ru
HE
RO
It's as if a hero is awakening on the inside
마음 속의 눈을 뜬 영웅들이여
tobitatsu no da furimukazu ni
to
bi
ta
tsu
no
da
fu
ri
mu
ka
zu
ni
Fly away and don't look back!
뒤돌아보지 말고 날아가라
DAGWON kagayake DAGWON
DA
G
WON
ka
ga
ya
ke
DA
G
WON
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Brave Command Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Dagwon... Shine on!! Dagwon!
다그온 빛나라!! 다그온
heiwa mamoru namae sa
he
i
wa
ma
mo
ru
na
ma
e
sa
The name that protects the peace
평화를 지키는 이름이다
DAGWON oretachi DAGWON
DA
G
WON
o
re
ta
chi
DA
G
WON
Dagwon! We are Dagwon!
다그온 우리는 다그온
yume wa zettai watasanai
yu
me
wa
ze
t
ta
i
wa
ta
sa
na
i
We will never hand over our dream
꿈은 절대로 넘겨줄 수 없다
afureru yuuki te ni shitai nara
a
fu
re
ru
yu
u
ki
te
ni
shi
ta
i
na
ra
To grab the overflowing courage
넘쳐흐르는 용기를 거머쥐고 싶다면
tsuyoku tsuyoku yuujou shinjiru koto sa
tsu
yo
ku
tsu
yo
ku
yu
u
jo
shi
n
ji
ru
ko
to
sa
We believe in our friendship firmly
우리 우정을 굳게 믿는 거다
kizutsuku koto mo osore wa shinai
ki
zu
tsu
ku
ko
to
mo
o
so
re
wa
shi
na
i
We are not afraid of getting hurt
상처입는 것도 두렵지 않아
mugendai no mirai wo egaku sono tame ni
mu
ge
n
da
i
no
mi
ra
i
wo
e
ga
ku
so
no
ta
me
ni
In order to reach that infinite future!
무한대의 미래를 그려내기 위해서라면
Vicious prisoners escaped from the Space Prison of Sargasso, and have begun their planetary galley.
우주 감옥 사르갓소의 흉악한 우주인들이 혹성 사냥을 개시했다
In order to protect the peace of Earth, Brave Seijin of the Space Police granted these six the brave powers of Dagwon.
지구의 평화를 지키기 위해 우주 경찰 기구의 브레이브 성인이 힘을 부여한 6명의 용자 다그온
And now, their new member is Gunkid!
그리고 새로운 동료는, 건키드!
History of Japan
일본사
Room 201
201 교실
Shin! Yoku!
신, 요쿠!
-Could it be...
-Gunkid?!
-설마?!
-건키드!
Hey! Hashiba, please come back!
이봐요!
하시바 군, 돌아오세요!
Oath of the Infinity Cannon
맹세의 무한포
Space Emperor Ark Seijin
Space Amoeba Chamelon
Appears
우주황제 아크 성인
우주 아메바 캬멜론 성인
등장
Th- this guy...!
이, 이게 뭐래냐?
Sorry for the trouble.
놀래켜서 미안하다
Gunkid and I will repair the cave.
동굴 수리는 나와 건키드가...
Lian, we entrusted the education of Gunkid to you.
라이안, 건키드의 교육은 너에게 일임했을 터다
Please explain what happened.
무슨 일인지 설명해 주세요
Forgive me.
용서해 다오
I was with him, but...
내가 옆에 있었는데도...
Apologize, Gunkid.
사과해라, 건키드
I didn't do anything bad.
난 잘못한 거 없는걸
Gunkid!
건키드!
But, some black animals on the ceiling...
그치만, 천장에 있는 시커먼 동물이...
Black animals?
시커먼 동물?
Those are bats.
박쥐겠지
They pooped on my body!
그녀석들이 내 몸에 똥을 떨어뜨리잖아
They offended me!
약이 올랐단 말야
Idiot!
멍청한 자식아!
You shot Vulcan cannon just to scare away the bats?!
박쥐를 쫓으려고 발칸포를 쏴댔다는 거냐?!
I hate you for being mad at me all the time!
넌 툭하면 화내서 싫어
Don't make me laugh!
웃기지마!
In the first place, Gunkid, you are...
애시당초 건키드, 넌 말야
Hey! Are you listening to me?!
이봐! 이놈아, 내 말 듣고 있냐?!
Hey! Hey!
이봐! 여봐!
Sorry.
미안하다
Is teaching an alien robot possible at all?
우주인의 로봇을 교육한다니 말야 역시 무리가 아닐까?
That bastard deserves to be disassembled!
저딴 녀석, 분해시켜 버려! 분해!
Please have patience!
기다려 다오
I'll teach Gunkid once again.
건키드에겐 내가 잘 말 해 볼게
He is still an innocent child who cannot distinguish what's good and what is not.
저녀석은 아직 뭐가 좋고 나쁜지도 모르는 순진무구한 꼬마일 뿐이야
He's not just a child.
단순한 꼬마가 아니야
More like an extremely destructive weapon.
걸어다니는 초 파괴 병기지
You came again!
또 왔구만!
Gunkid!
건키드!
Listen, Gunkid.
잘 들어라, 건키드
We all know that you were born as a destructive weapon.
분명히 넌 파괴 평기로써 제작되었어
But Gunkid, that is not so from now on.
하지만 건키드
지금은 아니야
Since you've became a friend of the earthlings, your weapon exists to protect your friends and yourself.
지구인의 친구가 된 이상 너의 무기는 지구의 친구들과 너 자신을 지키기 위해 존재하는 거야
You absolutely must not use it for other purposes.
그 이외의 목적으로는 절대 사용해서는 안돼
Lian...
라이안...
Can you promise with me?
나와 약속할 수 있어?
I understand, Lian! I promise.
알았어, 라이안!
약속할게
-What's wrong?
-What are you being lazy?!
-무슨 일이야?
-뭐하고들 있어?!
Come and protect the village!
마을에, 마을에 큰일이 일어났다구!
Did an alien appear?
우주인의 습격이냐?!
A tomato is raiding here!
토마토의 습격이다!
Geki, what is that?!
게키, 저게 뭐냐?
I told you! It's a tomato!
그러니까, 토마토라고 했잖냐!
Say something that doesn't sound so stupid!
바보같은 소리 말라구!
You call that monster a tomato?!
저런 괴물같은 게 토마토라구?
-Is that the tomato you said?
-I don't know!
-저게 토마토냐?
-나도 몰라!
It's coming back!
돌아오잖아!
Turbo Wheel Attack!
터보 호일 어택!
Breast Motor Cannon!
브레스트 모터 캐논!
Crystal Boomerang!
크리스탈 부메랑!
Big Spiral Whirlwind Slash!
대회전 검풍참!
I'm counting on you.
얘 좀 맡아줘
Fire Bird Attack!
파이어 버드 어택!
Wait.
기다려
What's wrong, Ryu?
왜그래, 류?
It's still alive.
녀석은 아직 살아있어
Is this its true form?
이게 녀석의 정체인가?
What the-?!
뭐, 뭐지?!
En!
엔!
Li- Lian!
라, 라이안!
What?!
아니?!
En! Go!
엔! 가라!
Fire Stratos!
파이어 스투라투스!
Be careful, En.
조심해라, 엔
We'll come as soon as we can.
우리도 서둘러서 갈게
That guy must be a space creature capable of reforming its cells as it wants.
필시 녀석은 세포를 자유롭게 변형시킬 수 있는 우주 생물일 겁니다
Do not attack even if you find it.
발견해도 공격하지 마라
If a gas tank is set on fire, then we're done for.
만에 하나, 가스 탱크에 불이 붙으면 큰일이야
I know.
알고 있어
A gas tank!
가스 탱크!
It has synchronized itself to the gas tank!
이녀석, 가스 탱크에 동화했어!
Here's my chance to save a comrade!
동료를 구할 기회다!
I'll get rid of that space creature!
우주 생물은 내게 퇴치할게!
That idiot!
저 바보녀석!
Gunkid! Don't shoot!
건키드! 쏘지마!
Don't shoot!
쏘면 안돼!
-Lian!
-라이안!
Lian!
라이안!
No!
아뿔싸!
You idiot.
바보같은 녀석
Did you think that you can take over the Earth simply by transforming yourself as much as possible?
닥치는 대로 변형해서, 지구를 정복할 수 있을 거라 생각하나?
Hmph. I should've expected that from a lower life.
흥, 하등 생물 주제에...
I'll teach you how to use your head!
머리를 사용하는 법을 가르쳐 주마
Become my obedient servant!
나의 종이 되거라!
That space creature ran away and Lian is severely wounded.
우주 생물은 도망가고, 라이안은 중상을 입었어
Gunkid! This is all your fault!
건키드! 이게 다 너 때문이라구!
I... I...
나... 나...
Forgive him.
요, 용서해 다오
Please forgive Gunkid.
건키드를... 용서해 다오...
Lian...
라이안...
Where are you going, Gunkid?
어디 가니, 건키드? 바이바이 라이안
엔 바보
Bye-bye
Lian
PS. En is a nerd
안녕
라이안
엔 바보
Gunkid!
건키드!
I am a robot anyway.
어차피 난 로봇이야
I am alone.
난 외톨이라구
I...
나 같은 건...
I shouldn't have even existed!
나 같은 건 태어나지 말았어야 했어!
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Original Korean Subtitles by Jaebari (재바리)
Translated to English by Subdivers
Checked by Great Exkaiser103
자막 원본(번역): 재바리
수정: Subdivers
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Gunkid!
건키드!
건키드...!
Come back! Gunkid!
돌아와! 건키드!
Gunkid...
건키드...
You are one silly guy.
바보같은 녀석
Where are you doing alone?
혼자서 어딜 가려는 거야?
What's wrong? Let's go back together.
왜 그래?
나와 함께 돌아가자
Now, Gunkid.
응? 건키드...
Gunkid...?
건키드...?
What?!
아니?!
Gunkid!
건키드!
En?!
엔?!
You always cause a ruckus!
나 참, 민폐나 끼치구 말야
Gunkid! Hurry up and get back to Dag Base!
건키드, 얼렁 다그 베이스로 돌아가!
How did you know I am here?
어떻게 여기 있는지 알았어?
Your cry is interfering with the radar over there!
네 울음소리가 저기 있는 레이더를 방해한단 말야
You're being noisy!
시끄러워 죽겠다구!
But... I left home!
그치만... 난 가출했단 말야!
You idiot! Lian has disappeared!
멍청한 놈아!
라이안이 사라졌어!
What did you say?!
뭐라고?!
How unsightly, Ken Seijin.
꼴사납구나, 검성인
You bastard...
네, 네놈은...
Ark Seijin!
아크 성인!
Lian!
라이안~
I will not die...
나, 나는 죽지 않는다...
Before...
네, 네놈을...
Before I take you down!
네놈을 쓰러뜨리기 전까지는...
What's the Sword Planet?
뭐가 검성이냐?
What's revenge?
뭐가 복수냐?
Don't make me laugh!
웃기지 마라!
Look at this.
이걸 봐라
That sword...!
그, 그 검은?!
has already died.
이미 죽었다
These are the last days of Ken Seijins like you.
이것이 너희들 검성인의 말로다
You bastard...
이자식...
Go to the hell where 2 billion of your comrades lie!
20억의 동포가 기다리는 지옥으로... 가거라!
That's...
음, 저건?
Lian!
라이안!
Lian! Lian!
라이안... 라이안!
Hey, Lian! Please!
이봐, 라이안! 라이안!
Open your eyes!
눈 좀 떠 봐!
Lian!
라이안!
Gunkid...
건키드...
The last Ken Seijin is now dead.
최후의 검성인은 죽었다
The Sword Planet has been annihilated.
검성은 전멸했다
-You bastard!
-How dare you!
-이자식!
-잘도 라이안을...!
Why you-! Why you-!
에잇! 에잇!
How's this?!
이건 어떠냐!
Fire Jumbo!
파이어 점보!
Blazing Fusion!
화염합체(火炎合體)
Fire Dagwon!
파이어 다그온
Gunkid, Change!
건키드 체인지!
Gunkid! Fight for Lian!
건키드!
라이안의 원수를 갚자!
I will fight!
원수를 갚자!
Eat this!
받아라~!
Wh- what?!
아, 아니?!
Lian?!
라, 라이안?
You fell into my trap!
함정에 걸렸구나
No way...
그럴수가...
Damn!
젠장!
-That's...
-저, 저건?!
-Lian!
-라이안!
N- no way... Then...
이, 이럴수가...
그렇다면...
I see... it's the space creature from before!
그렇군, 그때의... 우주 생물이야!
You are correct.
그 말대로다
How cowardly!
비겁한 녀석!
Energy, check.
에너지 잔량 OK
This is the end, Fire Dagwon!
마지막이다, 파이어 다그온!
Why? Fire the Infinity Cannon!
왜 그러나?
무한포를 발사해라!
-I won't!
-What?!
-싫어!
-뭣이?
I must not shoot a comrade!
동료를 쏘면 안돼!
I promised Lian!
라이안하고 약속했어!
Gunkid!
건키드!
You brat...
이놈...
Unforgivable!
용서치 않겠다!
Gunkid!
건키드!
What the-?!
뭐지?!
Now! Run away, Gunkid!
지금이야!
도망쳐, 건키드!
-Are you alright, Fire Dagwon?
-Yeah.
-괜찮아, 파이어 다그온?
-아아
We'll take care of them.
녀석의 상대는 우리가 할게
You two go save Lian!
너희들은 라이안을...
Got it!
알았어
-Let's go!
-Yeah!
-간다!
-오우!
Lian!
라이안!
Lian... Lian!
라이안... 라이안!
Gunkid...
건키드...
Lian!
라이안!
Gu- Gunkid...
거, 건키드...
Lian!
라이안!
You... came back...!
너... 돌아왔구나...
Yes!
응!
Super Liner Dagwon! Shadow Dagwon!
슈퍼 라이너 다그온!
섀도우 다그온!
Go!
가...라...
Go, Gunkid!
가라, 건키드! 응!
That's as far as you go, Ark Seijin!
거기까지다, 아크 성인!
We're your opponents from here on!
이제부턴 우리가 상대해 주마!
Gunkid, change!
건키드 체인지!
Chamelon, protect me!
캬멜론, 날 지켜라!
Let's go! Infinity Cannon!
간다, 무한포(無限砲)!
Fire!
파이어!
It can't endure this!
치잇, 못 버티는군!
This is a present from us to Gunkid.
우리가 건키드에게 주는 선물이야
Gunkid, from now on, you are a respectable Dagwon.
건키드, 이걸로 너도 어엿한 다그온이야
En!
엔!
Everything went well for you, Gunkid.
잘 됐구나, 건키드
Yeah!
응!
What a moving scene!
감동하게 만드는 광경이구만!
Just take it. It's yours now.
아악;; 됐어요. 드릴게요;;;
I feel weird.
이상해, 나...
Even though I am really happy, I wanna cry.
정말 기쁜데...
왠지 울고 싶어져
Hey, yo- you dolt! If you cry...
머, 멍청아! 네가 울면 말이야...
Please stop!
제발 그만둬!
The sun suddenly called me
태양이 갑작스레 나를 불러내서
taiyou ga fui ni ore wo izanau
To come to the blue sea
푸르게 비치는 바다로 만나러 갔지
aoku sukitooru umi ni ai ni kita
The ripples are coming and going
밀려왔다 돌아가는 잔물결
yosete wa kaesu sazanami
An endless melody
멈추지 않는 멜로디
tomaru koto nai MELODY
sono sugata towa ni tsunagu you ni
To keep that shape for eternity
그 모습을 영원히 유지할 수 있도록
I'll follow the fate of the dream
꿈의 행방을 뒤쫓아 갈 거야
oikakete yuku yo yume no yukue
Sparkling far away
멀리서 반짝이던
tooku kirameita
kaze no naka no PRISM
A Prism in the Wind
바람 속의 프리즘
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Preview for Next Episode
용자지령
다그온
차회예고
An eyeball-looking alien named Demakka Seijin appeared in my room.
내 방에 데맛카 성인이 나타났어
What?! What does it want?!
뭐야!? 그녀석이 노리는 게 뭐야?
This guy's a good alien. It says that an evil alien is looking for him so it wants to hide on the Earth.
그녀석은 착한 우주인이야 나쁜 우주인이 노리고 있어서, 지구에 숨겨달래
Be careful. It's probably planning something.
조심해, 분명 뭔가를 꾸미고 있을 거야
You doubt everything all the time. It's your bad habit.
곧잘 의심한다니까, 엔의 나쁜 버릇이야
Next time on Yuusha Shirei Dagwon! Targeted Gaku
다음회 용자지령 다그온
노려진 가쿠
What the-?!
아앗 이녀석!
It attacked me all of a sudden!
갑자기 나를 습격했어!
Told you!
거 보라구!
Targeted Gaku
노려진 가쿠